* Our storyOpen menu
* [Ukraine](https://commuapp.fi/en/ukraine/)Open menu
* [English](#pll_switcher)Open menu

Menu

* Our storyOpen menu
* [Ukraine](https://commuapp.fi/en/ukraine/)Open menu
* [English](#pll_switcher)Open menu

Privacy Policy
==============

### **Ronsam Digital Oy Privacy Policy**

Our company name is Ronsam Digital Oy. This privacy policy will explain how our organization uses the personal data we collect from you when you use our services.

More information on security and data protection can be found on this portal:  
[https://app.safebase.io/portal/ff7b1f70-153c-41a3-af39-2cfa0f49bdd3/preview?product=default](https://app.safebase.io/portal/ff7b1f70-153c-41a3-af39-2cfa0f49bdd3/preview?product=default)  
This document and the information on the portal form a whole.

This privacy policy covers following services provided by Us:

* [https://370c.l.time4vps.cloud/](https://370c.l.time4vps.cloud/) & [https://office.commuapp.fi/](https://office.commuapp.fi/)
* [https://yhteiskuntavastuu.info](https://yhteiskuntavastuu.info/) Impact profiles for companies.
* Commu – mobile application & web application ([https://app.commuapp.fi](https://app.commuapp.fi/))
* Our Facebook marketplace for business page

Topics:

* What data do we collect?
* How do we collect your data?
* How will we use your data?
* How do we store your data?
* Marketing
* What are your data protection rights?
* What are cookies?
* How do we use cookies?
* What types of cookies do we use?
* How to manage your cookies
* Privacy policies of other websites
* Changes to our privacy policy
* How to contact us
* How to contact the appropriate authorities

### **What data do we collect?**

Our Company collects the following data:

* Personal identification information
    * Your name (the one you give)
    * Your email address
    * Your address, if given
    * Profile picture, if given
    * Your last known location
    * Your IP address
    * Your personal ID (SSN), if you are authenticating thorugh a strong identification methods.
* Chats you do with other users inside the app
* Information that you enter in notices
* How often you open the app
* Visits to web pages, in anonymous format.
* Email opens and clicks to links

### **How do we collect your data?**

You directly provide Our Company with all of the data we collect. We collect data and process data when you:

* Register online or place an order for any of our products or services.
* Voluntarily complete a customer survey or provide feedback on any of our message boards or via email.
* Open our emails (we use technique known as email pixel)
* Use or view our website via your browser’s cookies.
* Use our application and/or functions within it that provide information to us.

### **How will we use your data?**

Our Company collects your data so that we can:

* Make app function
* Improve app functionality
* Improve the security of interactions in the app.
* Process your order and manage your account.
* Email you with special offers, news and important updates. We also email you instructions on how to best use the app.
* Understand how our campaigns, emails and ads are working
* Understand how users are using the app

Below is the comprehensive list of how we use the data we collected, sectioned by the category they belong to.

**Functional only**

Data in this category is collected and used entirely for providing the features of the platform. It’s never used for marketing, analytics or any other activities that are not needed for app to function.

* Address
    * Used for providing the ability to easily give address details to other user.
*  Last known location
    * Used for finding new notices near you when access to location from the app directly is not an option. Note: we DO NOT store your real time location, only the location you had when opening the app.
* Chats
    * Used for providing chat feature
* Information that you enter in notices
    * Used for providing users with information about helping possibilities.
* Profile picture
    * Used for a feature that allows users to add a unique image to their profile.
* Personal ID (SSN)
    * We only receive this information if you carry out strong authentication in the application. The ID is stored in a double encrypted form and is not used by the software automatically for any purpose.

**Analytics**

Data in this category is used for understanding how our services are used, which functionalities are actively used, how our website content is working etc. We collect analytics to create better services, improve user experience, examine how our emails are received and for understanding how our marketing campaigns are working.

* How often you open the app
    * Used for better understanding how many active users we have and which of our users are active ones.
* Email opens and clicks to links
    * Used for understanding which of our emails do better than others and how many clicks do we get to buttons and links inside these emails. We use this knowledge to provide better and more interesting communications from us.
* Visits to web pages, in anonymous format.
    * We use this data to understand what parts of our website are viewed as interesting and what parts are easy to find and which ones are not. It is also used for tracking referrers and forwards, meaning that we can better understand how our campaigns are doing and how well we convert users from our website to users.
* Your IP address
    * Used for providing geographical information on website visits. Can also be used for security purposes (IP blocking, Geo-blocking, known malicious IPs etc,).

**Functional & analytics & marketing**

Data in this category is used for multiple purposes.

* Your name
    * Used for providing identifiers for your user profile, within the app so that users know who they are dealing with and how to address you. (functional)
    * We may use your name when addressing marketing messages to you. (marketing)
    * We may use your name as an identifier when we analyze app usage, either in bulk format or of specific users. (analytics)
* Your email address
    * Used as your username for the app. Email address is unique for all users (functional)
    * Used for providing you with important messages related to app, eg. email verification, password resets, new messages, instructions on how to use the app, updates to privacy policy etc. (functional)
    * Used for providing you with interesting offers and news. (marketing)
    * We may use your email address as an identifier when we analyze app usage, either in bulk format or of specific users. (analytics)

When Our Company processes your order, it may send your data to, and also use the resulting information from, credit reference agencies to prevent fraudulent purchases.

### **How do we store your data?**

Our Company securely stores your data at datacenters located in Lithuania and Sweden. All servers are at least TIER III servers and have constant surveillance. 

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website, we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information. Users also have the right to be forgotten.

Newsletter (insider group) subscriptions and data given when subscribing into them is stored until the user exits the newsletter herself.

Form entries will be cleared after two years, but any email discussions that start from these form entries are stored on email servers indefinitely.

Google Analytics data will be removed within 26 months.

Facebook Custom Audiences data exists for 180 days.

### **Marketing**

Our Company would like to send you information about products and services of ours that we think you might like. 

If you have agreed to receive marketing, you may always opt out at a later date.

You have the right at any time to stop Our Company from contacting you for marketing purposes or giving your data to other members of the Our Company Group (currently none). We also do not currently have any partner companies with whom we share personal data for marketing purposes.

If you no longer wish to be contacted for marketing purposes, please send us an email ([company@commuapp.fi](mailto:company@commuapp.fi)). You can also opt-out of marketing communications through Commu app in case you are registered user.

### **What are your data protection rights?**

Our Company would like to make sure you are fully aware of all of your data protection rights. Every user is entitled to the following:

**The right to access** – You have the right to request Our Company for copies of your personal data. We may charge you a small fee for this service.

**The right to rectification** – You have the right to request that Our Company correct any information you believe is inaccurate. You also have the right to request Our Company to complete the information you believe is incomplete.

**The right to erasure** – You have the right to request that Our Company erase your personal data, under certain conditions.

**The right to restrict processing** – You have the right to request that Our Company restrict the processing of your personal data, under certain conditions.

**The right to object to processing** – You have the right to object to Our Company’s processing of your personal data, under certain conditions.

**The right to data portability** – You have the right to request that Our Company transfer the data that we have collected to another organization, or directly to you, under certain conditions.

If you make a request, we have one month to respond to you. If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please contact us:

Call us at: +358 45 8401336

Or write to us: [company@commuapp.fi](mailto:company@commuapp.fi)

Contact Person: Ronnie Nygren 

### **Cookies**

Cookies are text files placed on your computer to collect standard Internet log information and visitor behavior information. When you visit our websites, we may collect information from you automatically through cookies or similar technology

For further information, visit allaboutcookies.org.

#### **How do we use cookies?**

Our Company uses cookies in a range of ways to improve your experience on our website, including:

* Keeping you signed in
* Storing your preferred locale
* Understanding how you use our website
* Where did you come to our website (campaign tracking)

#### **What types of cookies do we use?**

There are a number of different types of cookies, however, our website uses:

* **Functionality** – Our Company uses these cookies so that we recognize you on our website and remember your previously selected preferences. These could include what language you prefer and location you are in. A mix of first-party and third-party cookies are used.
* **Advertising** – Our Company uses these cookies to collect information about your visit to our website, the content you viewed, the links you followed and information about your browser, device, and your IP address. Our Company sometimes shares some limited aspects of this data with third parties for advertising purposes. We may also share online data collected through cookies with our advertising partners. This means that when you visit another website, you may be shown advertising based on your browsing patterns on our website.

#### **Facebook tracking pixel**

We use the “visitor action pixels” from Facebook Inc (1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA, or, if you are based in the EU, Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland (“Facebook”)) on our website. This allows user behavior to be tracked after they have been redirected to the provider’s website by clicking on a Facebook ad. This enables us to measure the effectiveness of Facebook ads for statistical and market research purposes. The data collected in this way is anonymous to us, i.e. we do not see the personal data of individual users. However, this data is stored and processed by Facebook, which is why we are informing you, based on our knowledge of the situation. Facebook may link this information to your Facebook account and also use it for its own promotional purposes, in accordance with Facebook’s Data Usage Policy [https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/). You can allow Facebook and its partners to place ads on and off Facebook. A cookie may also be stored on your computer for these purposes. The legal basis for the use of this service is Art. 6 paragraph 1 sentence 1 letter f GDPR. You can object to the collection of your data by Facebook pixel, or to the use of your data for the purpose of displaying Facebook ads by contacting the following address: [https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads](https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads).

We guarantee the adequacy of data transfer to the third country USA through the agreement of EU standard contractual clauses.

#### **Google Analytics**

We use the Google Analytics service from Google Ireland Limited (Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland; “Google”) to analyze our website visitors. Google uses cookies. The information generated by the cookie about the use of the online product or service by users is generally transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there. Google will use this information on our behalf to evaluate the use of our online products and services by users, to compile reports on the activities within these online products and services and to provide us with further services associated with the use of these online products and services and the use of the internet. Pseudonymous user profiles can be created from the processed data. We use Google Analytics only with IP anonymization enabled. This means that Google will truncate the IP address of users within Member States of the European Union or in other states that are party to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and truncated there. The IP address transmitted by the user’s browser is not merged with other Google data. Users can prevent cookies from being stored by adjusting the settings to their browser software accordingly. The legal basis for the use of this service is Art. 6 paragraph 1 sentence 1 letter f GDPR. Users can prevent the collection of data generated by cookies by downloading and installing the browser plug-in that is available at the following link:  [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en). If you visit our website using a mobile device, you can deactivate Google Analytics by clicking on the following link: Click here.

A transmission of your data to the USA cannot be excluded. We guarantee the adequacy of data transfer to the third country USA through the agreement of EU standard contractual clauses.

#### **How to manage cookies**

You can set your browser not to accept cookies, and the above website tells you how to remove cookies from your browser. However, in a few cases, some of our website features may not function as a result.

**Other data processors**
-------------------------

We use Amazon Web Services EMEA SARL & Time4VPS as our cloud service provider.

Signicat AS processes your data when you perform strong authentication.

Your data may be processed by Google Cloud EMEA Limited and Slack Technologies, LLC, whose services we use for internal work.

We use Sendinblue (Brevo) to process email communications.

### **Privacy policies of other websites**

The Our Company website contains links to other websites. Our privacy policy applies only to our website, so if you click on a link to another website, you should read their privacy policy.

### **Changes to our privacy policy**

Our Company keeps its privacy policy under regular review and places any updates on this web page. This privacy policy was last updated on 26.03.2024.

### **How to contact us**

If you have any questions about Our Company’s privacy policy, the data we hold on you, or you would like to exercise one of your data protection rights, please do not hesitate to contact us.

Email us at: [company@commuapp.fi](mailto:company@commuapp.fi)

Call us: +358 45 840 1336

Contact Person: Ronnie Nygren 

### **How to contact the appropriate authority**

Should you wish to report a complaint or if you feel that Our Company has not addressed your concern in a satisfactory manner, you may contact the Office of the Data Protection Ombudsman.

Email: [tietosuoja@om.fi](mailto:tietosuoja@om.fi)

Phone: +358 29 566 6700

Address: Lintulahdenkuja 4, 00530 Helsinki

### **UPDATE HISTORY**

**26.03.2024**  
– Clarified a few data sharing related sentenced in marketing chapter to better indicate their purpose.  

**15.09.2024**

– Added Signicat as a processor and added SSN data information to what data is being proceesed

– Add safebase portal link for security portal.

#### Want to help us, hands on? Join Commu's Telegram group and be the first to know what happens behind-the-scenes.

Commu is a free mobile app where you can ask for help and give help in your neighborhood.

Download Commu now!

©2024 by Commu App

We use cookies on our website to make it work properly and to understand how it is used. By pressing "accept", all cookies are enabled

Reject AllCookie SettingsAccept All

Manage consent

Close

#### Privacy Overview

This website uses cookies to improve your experience while you navigate through the website. Out of these, the cookies that are categorized as necessary are stored on your browser as they are essential for the working of basic functionalities of the website. We also use third-party cookies that help us analyze and understand how you use this website. These cookies will be stored in your browser only with your consent. You also have the option to opt-out of these cookies. But opting out of some of these cookies may affect your browsing experience.

Necessary

 Necessary

Always Enabled

Necessary cookies are absolutely essential for the website to function properly. These cookies ensure basic functionalities and security features of the website, anonymously.

Functional

 Functional

Functional cookies help to perform certain functionalities like sharing the content of the website on social media platforms, collect feedbacks, and other third-party features.

Analytics

 Analytics

Analytical cookies are used to understand how visitors interact with the website. These cookies help provide information on metrics the number of visitors, bounce rate, traffic source, etc.

Advertisement

 Advertisement

Advertisement cookies are used to provide visitors with relevant ads and marketing campaigns. These cookies track visitors across websites and collect information to provide customized ads.

SAVE & ACCEPT
